# Ali Majedi

Data Scientist • +60 192877844 • aamajedi@gmail.com

Portfolio • Linkedin • Github

An ambitious and self-motivated person who enjoys finding unique approaches for solving different tasks. I can convey my ideas clearly and concisely in a team environment while being able to deliver quality projects with minimum supervision. As a graduate in BSc of AI I have experience working in different companies and startups on variety of projects related to machine learning, data modeling and recommendation systems.

# **Skills**

Java

Sklearn

Github

MySQL

Python

TensorFlow

• HTML

OpenCV

## **Education**

2016/09 - 2020/07

**Bachelor of Science: Artificial Intelligence** 

University of Malaya- Malaysia

3.6/4 CGPA

2015/09 - 2016/06

**Pre-University: Mathematics Major** 

Iranian School in Kuwait - Kuwait 94.05/100 Average Grade

# **Work History**

2020/05 - 2020/08

## **AI Engineer Internship**

Key ASIC Bhd, Malaysia

- Achieved 64% accuracy on blood cell image classifier by combining different pre-processing techniques and transfer learning
- Improved Bilirubin prediction model accuracy to 90% by using multi-linear regression model

2019/01 – 2019/10

# **AI Engineer Part-time**

Fylix, Malaysia

- Developed and deployed generic data extraction tool by enabling users to train the model on input samples and output template
- Designed database structure based on information acquired

#### 2018/08 - 2019/01

### Al Engineer Internship

Fylix, Malaysia

- Developed customized data extraction tool with up to 95% accuracy
- Improved extraction performance by developing a custom string matching algorithm
- Expanded supported document formats to Excel, Word and PDF by utilizing multiple libraries and APIs such as Apache POI and ABBYY
- Developed live data crawler and sentiment analysis tool
- Developed the website front-end by using Servlet, HTML, Java and CSS

# **Projects**

# Hybrid movie recommender

- Avoided cold-start problem by applying Collaborative Filtering
- Personalized the recommendation by tweaking the 1500 data points after each recommendation loop
- Improved recommendation performance by calculating genre correlation and including it as an attribute
- Improved recommendation speed by applying Bag-Of-Word and KNN and reducing dimensions with KNN in the background
- Achieved 82% recommendation accuracy by combining the mentioned techniques

# Forecast cryptocurrency price movement using historical data and Reddit submissions

- Scraped Reddit submissions using Pushshift, PRAW and Reddit API dating back to 2017 for more than 20 subreddits
- Scraped cryptocurrency prices from Binance for over 10 coins in multiple timeframes in a custom database
- Preprocessed and encoded the submissions using BERT algorithm
- Achieved over 70% forecast accuracy by training an LSTM model on historical data and Encoded features
- Optimized the database and algorithm to stream data from database for maximum efficiency during training as well as enabling real-time scraping and prediction

#### **Statement Generator**

 Developed a personal statement generator by having it learn text patterns and grammar from input data